suitecrm.com 2019-04-22

# Privacy Policy - SuiteCRM

SalesAgility Ltd. (“SalesAgility”) operates several websites including suitecrm.com. It is SalesAgility’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. We take all reasonable care to prevent any unauthorized access to and use of your personal data. Our staff maintain a responsibility to keep your information confidential and will only use it to offer relevant products and services related to your inquiry.

## Our Cookies Policy

By using this website you are consenting to our use of the cookies outlined below. We are not responsible for the use or data collected in any cookies set by third parties. Details of how to control and delete cookies are listed below.

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Cookies are not programs and therefore cannot contain viruses or other malicious software. They are purely a string of text and numbers. This website uses cookies as outlined below to help tailor and make our website and your browsing experience better.

## What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?

Like most website operators, SalesAgility collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. SalesAgility’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how SalesAgility’s visitors use its website. From time to time, SalesAgility may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

SalesAgility Productivity only collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on suitecrm.com blogs or suitecrm forum. SalesAgility only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses and email addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

## Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to SalesAgility’s websites choose to interact with SalesAgility in ways that require SalesAgility to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that SalesAgility gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who request a demo at suitecrm.com to provide data like a name and email address. SalesAgility does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

## How do we use your information?

SalesAgility may collect anonymous statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, SalesAgility may monitor the most popular articles on the suitecrm.com site.

We use the self-hosted marketing automation tool Mautic to improve the experience of the visitors. A visitors remain anonymous in the self-hosted Mautic, until they decide to interact with us via a form, providing us with their personal data. Once the visitor has left his data, we may use it to provide automatic email replies and personalized content (for example, an automatic email reply when a demo is requested).

SalesAgility does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

## How do we protect Certain Personally-Identifying Information?

SalesAgility discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors, and affiliated organizations that

  1. need to know that information in order to process it on SalesAgility’s behalf or to provide services available at SalesAgility’s websites, and
  2. that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; we will follow GDPR guidelines for the transfer of such information to them. SalesAgility will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors, and affiliated organisations, as described above, SalesAgility discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a witness summons, court order, or other governmental request, or when SalesAgility believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of SalesAgility, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of a SalesAgility website and have supplied your email address, and you have opted in for “I wish to get monthly up-to-date info about SuiteCRM releases, security patches and other SuiteCRM news”, SalesAgility may send you a monthly email to keep you up to date about SuiteCRM related news. If you have opted in for “I wish to get info about SuiteCRM support options and SuiteAssured” SalesAgility may occasionally send you an email to tell you about professional services, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with SalesAgility and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. SalesAgility takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

## Do we use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. Cookies are used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to:

  * Understand and save user’s preferences for future visits.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. **We do not use third-party services like Google Analytics** that track this information on our behalf, but we use Piwik, a self-hosted open source web analytics software that respects users privacy, and Mautic, a self-hosted marketing automation tool, that anonymously tracks visitors, until those visitors filled in a form, and becoming “known” visitors that accepted the privacy policy.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer or firefox) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies settings.

If you disable cookies, some minor features might be disabled.

## Controlling or deleting cookies

Depending on which web browser you use it is possible to control how cookies are used or to delete existing cookies from your computer. You can find instructions on how to control the use of cookies, or remove cookies from your computer at [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "External link to http://www.aboutcookies.org").

All modern browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be found in the ‘options’ or ‘preferences’ menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise, you should use the ‘Help’ option in your browser for more details.

Please remember that if you delete or restrict cookies from this website you may not be able to experience the full benefit of some of the features and services this website has to offer.

## According to the California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA) we agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously.

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our Privacy Policy Page.

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us
  * By calling us

## How does our site handle do not track signals?

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

## Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?

We do not allow or employ third-party behavioral tracking. Our website features no third party ads or tracking tools.

## Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices, should a data breach occur we will notify the users via email within 7 business days

We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

## CAN SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

  * ### To be in accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:

    * NOT use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
    * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
    * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.
    * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
    * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
    * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

## Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## Third-party links

We do not include or offer third-party products or services on our website

## Online Demo

Our online demo allows you to try out SuiteCRM. The demo automatically resets every hour. You can insert data, upload documents etc., but before you start, please keep the following in mind:

  * Don’t upload any private or sensitive information. The demo is shared with other users, and sessions and data may be logged for performance and testing reasons.
  * This demo is running on our servers, which will be upgraded fairly regularly. This allows you to try out the latest edition, but on the other hand can result in data loss.
  * The service may disappear at any time.

## SuiteCRM Forum

Our visitors can register for the online forum, where they can exchange information and participate in the SuiteCRM community. The forum uses functional cookies to keep a visitor logged in. It also records IP addresses in order to protect the forum from spam. A forum user can cancel their own account any time, either directly from the forum (when logged in) or by contacting us (see contact information below).

## Contacting us via social media

We use a third party provider, Hootsuite to manage our social media interactions.

If you send us a private or direct message via social media the message will be stored by Hootsuite for three months. It will not be shared with any other organisations.

## Emailing us

We use Transport Layer Security (TLS) to encrypt and protect email traffic. If your email service does not support TLS, you should be aware that any emails we send or receive may not be protected in transit.

We will also monitor any emails sent to us, including file attachments, for viruses or malicious software. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send is within the bounds of the law.

## Making online payments at our website

We use Stripe for handling online payments. The payment data will be stored by Stripe. For more information, please see the [Privacy Policy of Stripe](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy).

## Children’s personal data

Our website and services are not aimed at children, but at adults. SuiteCRM is Business Software. We do not wish to hold any data of minors under 13 and will proceed to the immediate deletion of any personal data of them. We do allow children of 13 and above to use the website and services, for, for example, intern ship requests, requests of info for projects they work on, etcetera.

## Unsubscribing

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can email us at [info@salesagility.com](mailto:info@salesagility.com) or follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and we will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

## Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy, please [contact us via this website form](https://suitecrm.com/about/about-us/contact/ "Contact us today") or by using the information below.

SalesAgility Ltd.

The Steeple, 65 King Street  
Stirling, Stirling FK8 1DT  
Scotland  
0044 1786 585 499

Last Edited on 2018-05-08
